{
    "exam_name": "OOPs Set 8",
    "total_marks": 20,
    "time_limit": 20,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>int add(int a, int b) {<br>    return a + b;<br>}<br><br>double add(double a, double b) {<br>    return a + b;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    int result = add(2.5, 3.5);<br>    cout << result;<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "6",
          "B": "6.0",
          "C": "6.5",
          "D": "Compile Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>void print(int a) {<br>    cout << \"int: \" << a << endl;<br>}<br><br>void print(double b) {<br>    cout << \"double: \" << b << endl;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    char c = 'A';<br>    print(c);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "int: A",
          "B": "double: A",
          "C": "A",
          "D": "Compile Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>template <typename T><br>void display(T value) {<br>    cout << \"Template: \" << value << endl;<br>}<br><br>void display(int value) {<br>    cout << \"Non-template: \" << value << endl;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    float f = 3.14;<br>    display(f);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "Template: 3.14",
          "B": "Non-template: 3.14",
          "C": "3.14",
          "D": "Compile Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int x = 10;<br>    {<br>        int x = 20;<br>        cout << x << \" \";<br>    }<br>    cout << x;<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "10 20",
          "B": "20 20",
          "C": "20 10",
          "D": "10 10"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int arr[] = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5};<br>    int *ptr = arr;<br>    cout << *ptr++ << \" \" << *ptr;<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "1 2",
          "B": "1 3",
          "C": "2 2",
          "D": "2 3"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>void print(int a);<br>int main() {<br>    char c = 'A';<br>    print(c);<br>    return 0;<br>}<br><br>void print(double b) {<br>    cout << \"double: \" << b << endl;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "Compile Error",
          "B": "int: 65",
          "C": "double: 65",
          "D": "No output"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>class Demo {<br>public:<br>    static int count;<br>    Demo() { count++; }<br>};<br>int Demo::count = 0;<br>int main() {<br>    Demo var1;<br>    Demo var2[5];<br>    cout << var1.count;<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "6",
          "B": "0",
          "C": "1",
          "D": "5"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int var = 2;<br>    do {<br>        cout << var;<br>    } while (var++);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "2",
          "B": "21",
          "C": "22",
          "D": "Infinite Loop"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>void display(int x) {<br>    cout << \"int: \" << x << endl;<br>}<br><br>void display(double y) {<br>    cout << \"double: \" << y << endl;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    char c = 'A';<br>    display(c);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "int: 65",
          "B": "double: 65",
          "C": "Compile Error",
          "D": "Ambiguity Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>void show(int x) {<br>    cout << \"int: \" << x << endl;<br>}<br><br>void show(double y) {<br>    cout << \"double: \" << y << endl;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    int n = 3;<br>    show(n);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "int: 3",
          "B": "double: 3.0",
          "C": "3",
          "D": "Compile Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>template <typename T><br>void process(T value) {<br>    cout << \"Template: \" << value << endl;<br>}<br><br>void process(double value) {<br>    cout << \"Double: \" << value << endl;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    process(5);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "Template: 5",
          "B": "Double: 5",
          "C": "5",
          "D": "Compile Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int a = 10;<br>    if (int a = 20) {<br>        cout << a << \" \";<br>    }<br>    cout << a;<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "10 20",
          "B": "20 20",
          "C": "20 10",
          "D": "10 10"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>struct Demo {<br>    int var;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    Demo str;<br>    Demo *ptr;<br>    ptr = &str;<br>    ptr->var = 100;<br>    cout << ptr->var;<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "100",
          "B": "Memory address of var",
          "C": "Compile Error",
          "D": "L-value Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int i = 0;<br>    while (i < 5) {<br>        cout << i;<br>        if (i == 2) {<br>            i = 2.5;<br>        }<br>        i++;<br>    }<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "Compile Error",
          "B": "012",
          "C": "012345",
          "D": "01234"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>void show(int x);<br>int main() {<br>    show(5.5);<br>    return 0;<br>}<br><br>void show(double y) {<br>    cout << \"double: \" << y << endl;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "Compile Error",
          "B": "int: 5",
          "C": "double: 5.5",
          "D": "No output"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int var = 5;<br>    cout << var-- << \" \" << var;<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "5 4",
          "B": "5 5",
          "C": "4 4",
          "D": "4 5"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int var = 0;<br>    do {<br>        cout << var;<br>    } while (var++);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "0",
          "B": "1",
          "C": "Infinite Loop",
          "D": "Compile Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int calculate(int x, int y) {<br>    return x + y;<br>}<br><br>double calculate(double x, double y) {<br>    return x * y;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    cout << calculate(2.5, 3);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "5.5",
          "B": "7",
          "C": "7.5",
          "D": "Compile Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br>    int i = 0;<br>    while (i < 5) {<br>        cout << i;<br>        if (i == 2) {<br>            i = 2.5;<br>        }<br>        i++;<br>    }<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "Compile Error",
          "B": "012",
          "C": "012345",
          "D": "01234"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?<br><br><pre>template <typename T><br>void display(T value) {<br>    cout << \"Template: \" << value << endl;<br>}<br><br>void display(int value) {<br>    cout << \"Non-template: \" << value << endl;<br>}<br><br>int main() {<br>    int x = 42;<br>    display(x);<br>    return 0;<br>}</pre>",
        "options": {
          "A": "Template: 42",
          "B": "Non-template: 42",
          "C": "42",
          "D": "Compile Error"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B"
      }
    ]
  }
  